我們是誰
Who are we?
難道我們只能活成別人期待的模樣
Are we simply what others want us to be?
無法逃脫既定的宿命
Are we destined to a fate beyond our control?
還是說  我們能夠進化
Or can we evolve?
超越自己
Become... something more?
1975年
你能換個頻道嗎
Can you change the station?
等這首歌放完  親愛的
When the song's over, honey.
兩首歌之前  你就這麼說了
You said that two songs ago.
這首可是經典老歌
You know this is a classic, right?
這樣吧  我答應你
Okay, how about I make you a promise?
等你長大  能自己開車了
When you're old enough to drive,
你想聽什麼歌都行
you can listen to whatever music you want.
行嗎
That a deal?
-約翰  -不是我
- John. - Wasn't me.
琴  是你幹的嗎
Jean, was that... Did you?
我什麼也沒幹
I didn't do anything.
-琴  你...  -我不知道  不是我
- Jean, what are you... - I... I don't know. It's not me.
安靜
Quiet.
Quiet!
她連塊皮都沒破
She doesn't have a scratch on her.
也沒有內傷
No internal injuries.
你確定她在事故車輛上嗎
And you're sure she was in the car?
確定
Yeah.
那這事兒誰通知她
Who's gonna tell her?
謝謝
Thank you.
你好
Hello.
我爸媽呢
Where are my parents?
-我叫查爾斯·澤維爾  -他們死了
- My name's Charles Xavier, and... - They're dead.
對嗎
Aren't they?
對  沒錯
Yes, they are.
我很抱歉  告訴你這個噩耗
And I'm very sorry to have to tell you that.
那我接下來會怎樣
So what happens to me now?
我就是為此事而來
Well, that's why I'm here, actually.
我開了一所學校
You see, I have a school
專門收像你一樣的孩子
that is for young people, who are like you.
特別之人
Special.
特別只是客氣話  用來代稱...
Special is just a nice word for...
怪胎  瘋子
Weird? Or crazy?
沒錯
Yep.
沒錯  有時是這樣
Yep, sometimes it is.
但有時也可以用來形容那些重要的人
Sometimes, it can be a word used to describe people who are significant.
了不起的人  或者...
Or amazing. Or...
或者是那些很棒的人
Or just... just really cool.
你有天賦  琴
You've got gifts, Jean.
是這樣
Do you know what?
拿著這支筆
Take this pen, right.
這支筆…
It's something that...
你就拿著吧
Well, actually, just take it.
這是禮物
It's a gift.
你可以用這支筆畫出一幅佳作
Now, you could choose to draw a really good picture with that...
也可以用來戳爆別人的眼睛
or you could use it to poke someone's eyes out.
但不管怎樣  這只是一支筆
But either way, it's still just a pen.
只是一個禮物[天賦]It's just a gift.
如何使用上天賜予你的禮物[天賦]And what you choose to do with your gift,
完全取決於你
well, that's entirely up to you.
但如果你想用天賦做善事
But if you want to use it to do good stuff...
我能幫你
Well, I can help.
你和其他醫生不一樣
You're not like the other doctors.
對
No.
你也和其他病人不一樣
And you're not like the other patients.
怎麼樣
What do you think?
我不能待在這兒
I can't stay here.
為什麼
Okay. Why not?
這裡太美好了
It's too nice.
我
I...
我總是會破壞
I break things.
這樣吧
Well, how does this sound:
如果你破壞了任何東西  我來修復
If you break something, anything, I can fix it.
不是一切都能修復
Not anything.
我能幫你
I can help you.
我幫你  你以後就再也不用破壞了
I can help you so that you never have to break things ever again.
你覺得你也能修好我
You think you can fix me too.
不
No.
不是那樣  因為你沒有毛病
No, because you are not broken.
十  九  八  七
Ten, nine, eight, seven,
六  五  四  三  二  一
six, five, four, three, two, one...
X戰警   黑鳳凰
1992年
發動機正在加速
Engines throttling up.
三臺發動機效能達到104%
Three engines now at 104%.
我偵測到了異常情況
Hey, I'm... I'm picking something up here.
長官  六號衛星  顯示異常
Ma'am, I've got something on sat six.
休斯頓  我們遇到麻煩了
Houston, we have a problem.
奮進號飛船在執行任務中遇到問題
Space Shuttle Endeavour has encountered problems on its mission.
-我知道你想怎樣  -我才是會讀心術的人
- I know what you're thinking. - That's my trick.
行不通  X戰艦飛不了那麼高
And the answer is no. The jet can't get that high.
加裝推進火箭  經過你的改裝後也不行嗎
Even with the new booster rockets and all your modifications?
那是用來加速  而非提升高度
They're built for acceleration, not elevation, okay?
這不可行
Not this. No.
推力矢量已經失去控制
They've lost thrust vector control.
軌道設置失常
Trajectory settings are irregular,
可能是發動機長時間工作造成
likely from the constant engine burn.
制氧系統也已停止運行...
Oxygen generation is down...
喂  我是
Yes? Yes, this is he.
-查爾斯  -總統先生
- Charles? - Mr. President.
你看到新聞了嗎
Are you seeing this on TV?
我正在看
Yes, I'm watching now.
漢克
Hank?
好
Yeah.
這是一次簡單的救援任務
It's a simple extraction.
我們上太空
We go into space,
救出宇航員  帶他們回來
we get the astronauts, we bring them home.
-有問題嗎  -有  大概上千個
- Any questions? - Yeah, like a thousand.
沒時間回答你上千個問題
We don't have time for a thousand.
我們要上太空
So we're going to space?
對  科特  我們要上太空
Yes, Kurt, we are going into space.
我們都接太空任務了  真帥
We're doing space missions now. Cool.
X戰艦能飛那麼高嗎
Will the X-Jet even get that high?
-技術上來說...  -可以
- Well, technically, the... - It will get us there.
走吧
Let's go.
你真覺得沒問題嗎
Are you okay with this?
我有時候會忘記你可以讀心
I forget sometimes you can read minds.
我不需要讀你的心
I didn't need to read your mind.
都寫在臉上了
It's written all over your face.
你說沒問題就行
You tell me it's good, it's good.
如果出了什麼狀況
If anything goes wrong,
我會帶大家立刻調頭
I'll turn us around in a heartbeat.
我知道你會
I know you will.
另一艘飛船已經發射升空
A second ship has been spotted in the sky.
據瞭解  總統召集了X戰警前來求援
We are being told the president has called in the aid of the X-Men.
航天局的各位同志們
Ladies and gentlemen of NASA,
我是查爾斯·澤維爾
this is the voice of Charles Xavier.
哪位告訴我一下最新的情況
Could somebody please apprise me of the situation?
我們探測到太陽耀斑
We were picking up solar flares.
應該是熱量導致電力系統短路
We believe the heat shorted out their electricity.
他們失去了控制  通信  導航  幾乎所有功能
They lost control, communication, orientation, pretty much everything.
指揮中心  不用擔心  救援已上路
Not to worry, Mission Control. Help is on the way.
這沒有我想像得那麼好玩
I think this is not as much fun as I thought it would be.
那是太陽耀斑嗎
That's a solar flare?
我從沒見過這樣的探測值
I've never seen a reading like this.
方位推進器熄火了
The orientation thruster's misfiring.
-船艙挺不了多久  -科特  你能進去嗎
- That cabin won't hold for long. - Kurt, can you get in there?
轉得太快  我看不清窗戶裡面
It's spinning too fast. I can't see inside the window.
斯考特  你去炸掉推進器  降低旋轉速度
Scott, I need you to blast that thruster, slow down the spin.
科特  帶上皮特  出發
Kurt, take Peter. Go!
暴風女  封住裂縫
Storm, seal those cracks.
馬上回來
Be right back.
糟糕
Shit.
-繫好安全帶  我們回家  -等等
- Strap in, we're headed home. - Wait.
我們的指揮官  他不在
Our commander, he's not here.
他在氣閥艙修推進器
He was in the airlock working on the thruster.
熱能指數飆升
The heat signature's rising fast.
我撐不住了
I can't hold it any longer.
趕緊離開  我說了  繫好安全帶
We gotta get out of here. I said strap in.
不  瑞雯  不行  我們不能拋下任何人
No, Raven. No. We're not leaving anyone behind.
我不能讓這個團隊冒險
I am not putting this team in more danger.
他們的團隊呢
What about their team?
琴能穩住那架飛船
Jean can hold that shuttle together.
可以吧  琴
Can't you, Jean?
你知道只要專注  你就無所不能
You know you can do anything you set your mind to.
我能穩住那架飛船  但在這裡不行
I can hold the ship together but not from here.
-我需要進去  -熱量爆表了
- I need to get inside. - The heat's spiking.
離耀斑爆炸不到一分鐘了
We've got less than a minute till those flares hit.
她說她能做到
She said she can do it.
給你們三十秒
Thirty seconds.
倒計時  開始
Count it down. Go.
我們有二十秒
We got 20 seconds.
十
Ten...
九  八
nine, eight...
七  六
seven, six...
五
five...
四
four...
三
three...
二
two...
一
one.
琴呢  科特  她人呢
Where's Jean? Kurt, where is she?
-她在哪  -對不起
- Where is she? - I'm sorry!
做好受沖準備
Brace for impact.
大家
Is every...
大家都沒事吧
Is everybody okay?
當然  我們都沒事
Yeah, we're okay.
那就回家吧
So let's go home.
-X戰警好棒  太厲害了  -好樣的
- Yay, X-Men! Woo! - Yeah!
厲害  X戰警
Yeah! X-Men!
好了  孩子們  可以了
That's enough, boys and girls. That's enough.
X戰警今天做了一件驚天動地的大事
The X-Men have today done an incredibly brave thing.
再次向人類證明了他們為什麼需要我們
They've once again proved to humanity exactly why they need us,
需要你們這樣的人
people like yourselves.
總統發來了問候
The president sends his regards,
並表達了誠摯的謝意
as well as his heartfelt gratitude.
至於我本人  我感到前所未有的驕傲
And, as for myself, I've never been prouder.
大家好好放鬆  這是你們應得的
Enjoy yourselves. You certainly deserve it.
事實上  你們也是
In fact, you all do.
停課  今天放假
No more class, the end of the day.
琴
Jean?
你今天把我們嚇壞了  你感覺怎麼樣
You gave us quite a scare up there. How are you feeling?
我感覺還挺好
Actually, I... I feel fine.
-漢克  -到
- Hank? - Yeah?
給琴做個檢查
Would you take a look at Jean?
外勤傷員的常規體檢就行
Standard medical for anyone injured in the field.
謝謝
Thank you.
總統差點就致以哀悼了
You know, the president was almost sending his condolences.
-她本該沒命了  -幸好  她沒有
- She should be dead. - Thankfully, she's not.
基本上都是哥的功勞
I basically did everything.
琴在最後也幫了一點小忙
I mean, Jean did a little, like towards the end,
但主要是靠哥逆轉乾坤
but it was mostly all me.
你讓我們以身犯險了  查爾斯
You put us in danger, Charles.
你不顧那些孩子的安危
You put those kids in danger.
他們已經不是孩子了  瑞雯
They're not kids anymore, Raven.
而且我和你一樣擔憂他們的安危
And I care about their safety just as much as you do.
你確定嗎
Are you sure about that?
我們接的任務越來越危險了
'Cause we're taking bigger and bigger risks.
為了什麼呢
And for what?
你可千萬別說這是為了你的自尊心
Please, tell me it's not your ego.
為了上雜誌封面
Being on the cover of magazines,
為了獲總統勛章
getting a medal from the president.
你很享受吧
You like it, don't you?
不被追殺  也不被人類唾棄
As opposed to being hunted and despised?
我確實覺得不錯
Well, you know, actually, I do.
不過是為了達到目的而已  瑞雯
It's all just a means to an end, Raven.
-什麼目的  -讓我們安全活著
- What end is that? - Keeping us safe.
你應該比誰都瞭解
You should understand better than anyone
只要稍有差池
that we're only ever one bad day away
我們就又會被人類仇視
from them starting to see us as the enemy again.
於是就讓我們穿著一樣的制服
So, what? We wear matching costumes
微笑合影  靠作秀安撫民心嗎
and smile in pictures to make everyone feel safe?
這只是為了相安無事的小犧牲
That is a small price to pay for keeping the peace.
-讓我們的人捨身救他們  -對  是的
- By risking our people to save theirs? - Yes! Yes!
真有意思
It's funny.
我都記不起來你上一次冒險是什麼時候了
I can't actually remember the last time you were the one risking something.
另外
And by the way,
這裡一直都是女人給男人擦屁股
the women are always saving the men around here.
你該考慮一下把隊名改成"X女戰警"了
You might wanna think about changing the name to X-Women.
心跳脈搏  穩定有力
Your heartbeat's strong, pulse is good,
大腦活動也正常
brain activity is normal.
至於基因數據  我得再看看
The genetic reading, I'm gonna take another look at.
什麼不可能
What can't be right?
你沒經我允許  就對我讀心了嗎
Did you just read my mind without permission?
對不起  無心之過  你說什麼不可能
Sorry, I didn't mean to, but what can't be right?
太空中那場不明事件  讓你變強了
Whatever happened up there made you stronger.
我從未見過像這種能量值
You know, I've never seen a power reading like this.
你真的是  數據爆表了
You're-You're literally... I mean, you're off the charts.
這是什麼意思
So what does that mean?
意思是
It means...
看來要建一個更先進的機器了
We'll have to build a better machine.
不過  你感覺如何
But... how do you feel?
我感覺挺好
I feel good.
那就好
Good.
就我看來  你沒事了
Well, as far as I can tell, you're good to go.
-你可以上樓了  -好
- You can head upstairs. - All right.
多謝了  漢克
Thanks, Hank.
漢克說的嗎
Hank said that?
-"數據爆表"  -是
- "Off the charts"? - He did.
那個藍毛大塊頭  那個博士漢克嗎
The big blue furry guy? The doctor? That Hank?
就是他  怎麼了
That's the one. Why?
你有點害怕嗎
You a little intimidated, maybe?
一直都是
Constantly.
琴  琴
Jean. Jean...
你確定自己沒事嗎
Are you... Are you sure you're okay?
我不僅沒事  我還感覺棒極了
I'm better than okay. God, I feel great, I do.
怎麼說呢  感覺一切都被激活了
I don't know, I feel like everything is just... turned up.
-不  只是  -只是什麼
- No, it's just... - Just what?
我今天差點失去你了
I thought I lost you today.
我知道
I know.
但我回到你身邊了
But I came back to you.
我永遠都會回到你身邊
I'll always come back to you.
是露娜在叫嗎
Is that Luna?
大概看到松鼠而已
Probably just squirrels.
我去看看她  馬上回來
I'm just gonna check on her. I'll be right back.
別走
Just stay.
-讓她安靜點  -露娜
- Tell her to shut up. - Luna!
露娜
Luna!
親愛的
Honey!
怎麼了  怎麼了  乖狗狗
What is it? What is it, honey?
他的笑聲最蠢了
He's got the dumbest laugh.
不是
That's not...
不是那麼回事
That's not how it happened.
-我的天啊  -那是...
- My God. - That was...
瑪格麗特
Margaret?
怎麼...
What...?
? 把手放入我的懷裡 ?
□ Put your hands on me □
? 來感受我的內心 ?
□ To marvel inside my heart □
? 讓世界更明亮些 ?
□ Make it come brighter □
? 我們的愛如此耀眼 ?
□ Our love is on fire □
? 熄滅所有燈光 ?
□ Turn all the lights out □
? 帶我去更高的地方 ?
□ Taking me higher □
? 把手放入  把手放入我的懷裡 ?
□ Put your hands on, put your hands on me □
-這邊  -好的
- This way. - Okay.
再來一杯嗎
One more?
好  我先喝完手裡這杯
Yeah, I'll go ahead and finish this one.
再去拿兩杯
Two more?
好
Yeah.
? 把手放入我的懷裡 ?
□ Put your hands on me □
來點冰塊
Rocks.
謝謝
Thanks.
-她怎麼樣了  -她很渴
- How is she doing? - She's... thirsty.
我看到了
Yeah, I see that.
你看著她像是沒事嗎
Does she seem okay to you?
對於剛被太陽耀斑擊中的人來說
For someone who's just been hit with solar flares...
-我覺得她看起來挺好  -謝謝
- I'd say she's doing pretty good. - Thanks.
不久以前
You know, it wasn't so long ago
我們也這樣在派對上狂歡
we were throwing parties like this.
現在只剩下我們
Now we're the only ones left.
是啊  原班人馬就只剩我們了
Yeah. Last of the first class.
我一直在考慮
I've been thinking.
我們也許該離開了
Maybe it's time for us to... move on.
什麼意思  離開去哪兒
What do you... Move on where?
我也不知道  只是查爾斯
I don't know. It's just Charles.
你們之間不管發生什麼  總會過去
Whatever is going on between you two, it will blow over.
不  不會
No, it won't.
我愛他  但他變了
I love him, but he's different.
現在一切都變了
Everything is... it's different now.
是啊
Yeah.
我們改變世界  才能得以生活
We changed the world so we could live in it.
也許我們該去過自己的生活
Yeah, but maybe that's what we should go do.
但這就是我們追求的人生
Yeah, but this is our life. This is what we wanted.
-不是這樣的人生  -瑞雯
- Not like this. - Raven...
這不是我們的人生  漢克  是他的人生
It's not our life, Hank. It's his.
不然你以為X戰警裡的"X"代表著什麼
What do you think the "X" in X-Men stands for?
危急時刻  總是查爾斯和他的X戰警逆轉乾坤
Charles and his X-Men are where we turn when facing our worst fears.
謝謝你  總統先生
Thank you, Mr. President.
謝謝你
Thank you.
我不過是創造了一個世界
All I've really done is create a world
使孩子們能夠平和而驕傲地接受自己的與眾不同
in which children can find peace and pride in being different.
我知道有些人會稱我們為"超級英雄"
Now, I know that some of you choose to call us "Superheroes."
我得承認  我真不知道這個詞是什麼意思
I must confess, I don't really know what that word means,
但總比你們過去對我們的稱呼好聽多了
but it is a damn sight better than what you used to call us.
-來一起跳個舞吧  -你想要跳舞
- Come dance with me. - You wanna dance?
來吧  斯考特
Come on, Scott.
你有聽到那些孩子們怎麼稱呼你嗎
Did... Did you hear what the kids are calling you?
-是好話嗎  -是
- Do I wanna know? - Yeah.
鳳凰
Phoenix.
很棒吧  一種浴火重生的鳥
It's cool, right? You know, a bird that rises from the dead.
你還好吧  不然我們休息下
You okay? Hey, maybe we should take a break.
琴
Jean.
等等  等等
Wait, wait, wait.
不  停下  停下  停下
No, stop, stop, stop, stop.
異常
琴
It's Jean.
琴  琴  求你了
Jean. Jean, please.
停下  停下  停下
Stop, stop, stop.
Stop, stop, stop!
-謝謝你  -謝謝你  查爾斯
- Thank you. - Thank you, Charles.
抱歉各位  我得先行告辭了
I'm terribly sorry, everyone, but I'm going to have to leave.
非常感謝你們
Thank you very, very much.
怎麼樣  你看到什麼了
What is it? What do you see?
我什麼都看不到
Nothing.
她的變異太過強大
Her mutation has grown too powerful.
這是我第一次無法看到她的思想
For the first time, I can't penetrate her mind.
所以才來這裡嗎
So that's what we're doing down here?
漢克造出了腦波增幅器來增強我的異能
Hank built Cerebro to amplify my power.
現在只能這樣進入她的大腦
I think that's the only way I'm going to get inside her head now.
漢克  能請你再增強一點嗎
Hank, could you turn it up, please?
再增強一點  謝了
A little more. Thank you.
她在那兒
There she is.
-沒錯  -很好吃吧
- Yes, it is. - Isn't that yummy?
這是正常顯示嗎
Is it supposed to look like this?
心靈意識本就是脆弱之物
The mind of a psychic is a fragile thing.
只需輕觸
It takes only the slightest tap
就足以帶入歧途
to tip it in the wrong direction.
她小時候  我必須修改她的記憶
I had to make adjustments to her mind when she was young.
什麼樣的修改
What kind of adjustments?
就像搭建腳手架
Scaffolding.
更像是築牆  隔絕所有心理上的創傷
Walls, rather, to keep out all the trauma.
查爾斯  你到底對她做了什麼
What did you do to her, Charles?
我救了她
I saved her.
太空中那場不明事故  對她造成了影響
I think that whatever happened in space did something to her.
這個過程中  我築起的牆壘漸漸倒塌
In the process, those walls that I erected are being torn down.
安靜
Quiet!
那是什麼
What is that?
那是我不願讓她憶起的傷痛
That... is what I was trying to save her from.
單人桌  老樣子
Table for one. My usual.
誰在說話
What is that voice?
-不  -查爾斯
- No... - Charles?
查爾斯
Charles?
她要醒過來了
She's waking up.
琴
Jean?
琴  不要害怕  只是我而已
Jean, don't be afraid. It's only me.
你要保持鎮定
I want you to remain calm,
專心聽我的聲音
and I'd like you to focus on my voice.
滾出我的大腦
Get out of my head.
琴  冷靜點
Just stay calm, Jean.
她在反抗我  幫我增強
She's fighting me. I need you to turn it up.
我聽見我父親聲音了
I heard my father.
-他還活著  -你聽錯了
- He's alive. - You're just hearing things.
琴  你的大腦需要休息
Jean, your mind, it needs rest.
你
You're...
你騙我
You're lying to me.
我能感受到
I can sense it.
增強
Turn it up.
-不行  已經太強了  -別增強  漢克
- No, it's too much already. - Don't do it, Hank.
-漢克  -不  我不會這麼做
- Hank. - No, I won't do it.
天吶  查爾斯
For God's sake, Charles!
滾出我的大腦
Get out of my head!
查爾斯
Charles!
-查爾斯  -查爾斯
- Charles! - Charles!
琴  你
Jean! Are you...
你還好嗎
Are you okay?
發生什麼了  我們之前在外面  然後
What happened? We were outside, and then...
你出了意外  然後昏過去了
You had an accident. You blacked out.
我讓你受傷了嗎
Did I... Did I do... do that?
沒關係
It's fine.
-有關係  -只是個意外
- No, it's not fine. - It was an accident.
我不知道自己怎麼了
I don't know what's happening to me.
我無法控制  我不能待在這裡  斯考特
I can't control it. I can't stay here, Scott.
我真得必須離開了
I really, I need to go.
你說什麼呢
What are you talking about?
-你要去哪兒  -我要去見
- Where are you going? - I need to see...
我要去見我父親
I need to see my father.
-你父親他  -他還活著  我聽見他了
- Your fa... Your father's... - He's alive. I can hear him.
他在那場車禍中喪生了  還記得嗎
He died in the crash, remember?
斯考特  抱歉  我必須走了
I'm sorry, Scott. I need to go.
-等等  -你就讓我走吧
- Hang on, hang on, hang on. - God, please let me go.
-求你了  -你冷靜一下
- Please. - Slow down, please.
這種力量來襲時  我無法控制  無法停下
I can't control it when it comes. I can't stop it.
到時可能又會傷到你
Okay? I could hurt you again.
我自願承擔後果
I'll take that chance.
我知道
I know.
但是我不願意
But I won't.
-他沒事嗎  -我沒事
- Is he gonna be all right? - I'm gonna be fine.
-不  他有事  -我不會有事
- No, he's not fine. - I'm going to be fine.
你看到了什麼
What did you see?
她充滿了慾望
She's all desire.
還有狂怒和痛苦
All rage, all pain.
所有情緒一同爆發
And it's all coming out at once.
瑞雯  她身上出問題了
Something's happening to her, Raven.
她變了
She's changing.
變成什麼
Into what?
我不知道
I don't know.
琴不見了  她走了
Jean's gone. She left.
-去哪兒了  -我不知道
- Gone where? - I don't know.
查爾斯  你可以用意念來追蹤她
Charles, you can track her with your mind.
沒法再追蹤了
Not anymore.
她現在太強大  我也無能為力了
She's grown too powerful, even for me.
她說她要去見她父親
She said she was going to see her father.
這根本說不通吧
That doesn't make any sense, right?
準備一下飛機  我們去把她帶回家
Prepare the jet. We're going to bring her home.
"我們"  查爾斯  你現在狀態不行
"We"? Charles, you're in no condition.
我必須阻止她  她會發現...
I have to stop this. She's going to find...
她去那裡  不會有好結果
She's going to find nothing good there.
德巴裡帝國就剩這些人了嗎
So this is all that's left of the D'Bari Empire?
你好  武克
Greetings, Vuk.
你掌握地球人的語言了嗎
Have you learned their language?
小菜一碟
With ease.
你有什麼發現
What have you learned?
那股力量蘊藏在他們中一人體內
The power is being contained inside one of them.
-竟然是個原始物種  -她比較厲害
- This primitive species? - She's stronger.
她是一個變種人
A mutant.
她對此還毫不知情
She has no idea what's happening to her.
我可以利用這一點
I can use that.
如果我們可以控制這股力量
If we can control that power...
就可以復活我們的種族了
we can resurrect our race.
東山再起
Begin again.
統治這裡
Here.
她在哪兒
Where is she?
你有什麼事嗎
Can I help you?
爸
Dad?
琴
Jean.
你怎麼知道要去哪裡  查爾斯
How do you know where we're going, Charles?
如果你沒法追蹤她  怎麼知道她在哪兒
If you can't track her, how do you know where she is?
你明知故問
You know how.
天吶
Jesus Christ.
你對她做了什麼
What did you do?
我那是保護她
I protected her.
向她隱瞞真相
From the truth.
說得這麼冠冕堂皇
There's another word for that.
他跟我說  你死了
He told me you were dead.
我從沒想過會回來這裡
I never thought I'd be back here.
家裡還是跟以前一樣
It's the same.
一點沒變
All of it.
你想吃點什麼  喝點什麼嗎
Can I get you something to drink or-or eat?
不用  我...
No, I'm good. I'm...
不用招待我了
I'm really good.
見到你真好
It's so good to see you.
我去給你倒杯水
I'll get you some water, okay?
安靜
Quiet.
琴
Jean?
這些照片裡  一張都沒有我
All these photos, none of me.
你從沒找過我
You never looked for me.
-琴  -你為什麼不來找我
- Jean... - Why didn't you look for me?
還是坐下來說吧
Maybe we should sit down.
不  我不要坐下
No, I don't wanna sit down.
你當年為什麼沒來找我
Why didn't you come looking for me?
別想騙我  我會讀心術
And don't try to lie. I can read your mind.
我沒法撫養她
I can't handle her.
我都不知道她是什麼
I don't even know what she is.
我知道
I do.
你會帶走她
Then you'll take her?
你都沒跟我告別
You didn't even say goodbye.
我當年也沒機會跟你媽告別
I didn't get a chance to say goodbye to your mother.
我當時才八歲
I was eight years old.
你怎麼能這樣對我
How could you do that to me?
你想讀我的大腦嗎
You wanna come in?
那就好好看看吧
Come all the way in.
別忘了你的所為
Don't forget what you did.
我不知道  不是我
I don't know. It's not me.
安靜
Quiet!
不  不
No. No.
抱歉  琴
I'm sorry, Jean...
我的世界在那一天崩塌了
but my whole world died that day.
我也當你死了
And... you went with it.
琴  別這樣
Jean, don't, please.
住手
Stop that.
Stop it.
不是我  是他們
It's not me. It's them.
你們不該過來
You shouldn't have come here.
怎麼這麼說  我們只是來帶你回家  琴
Why is that? We've only come to bring you home, Jean.
我沒有家了  都是拜你所賜
I don't have a home. You made sure of that.
你父親當時沒法撫養你
Look, your father couldn't handle you,
我們收留了你
and we took you in.
你跟我說  我父親死了
You told me my father was dead,
然後利用我的異能為你效勞
and you used me for my powers.
不是那樣  事實並非如此
No, that's just not true. That's not what happened.
琴  我們能幫你
Jean, we can help you.
我能幫你  但你得聽我的話
I can help you, but you have to listen to me.
不  我才不要
No. No, I don't.
斯考特
Scott.
他騙了我  斯考特  欺瞞了我一切
He lied to me, Scott. About everything.
我們一起想辦法  回到我身邊
We'll figure everything out together. Just come back to me.
你說過  你會永遠回到我身邊  記得嗎
Remember, you said you'd always come back to me.
回到我身邊吧
Come back to me.
琴
Jean.
別過來  都別過來
Stay away from me. Stay away from me.
別過來
Stay away from me!
-立刻阻止她  -查爾斯  等一下
- Stop her quickly! - Charles, wait, wait!
琴  別這樣
Jean, please!
琴  住手
Jean, stop!
-我瞄準了  可以...  -別開槍
- I've got the shot. I'm taking... - No, you're not.
抱歉  漢克  我想讓瑞雯勸服她
I'm sorry, Hank. I want Raven to have a chance.
我讓你別靠近了
I told you to stay away.
我做不到
That's never gonna happen.
你別再過來了
Please. Stop.
我必須先確保你沒事
Not until I know you're gonna be okay.
我身上出問題了
Something's happening to me.
那就回家
So come home.
我們來治癒你
Let me take care of you.
你做不到
No, you can't.
你不行  你不懂
You can't. You don't...
你不懂這種感覺
You don't know what it's like.
那就告訴我
Then tell me.
這種力量來襲時
When it comes...
身邊的人會受傷
people get hurt.
我不怕你  琴
I'm not afraid of you, Jean.
看著我
Look at me.
專心聽我的聲音
Focus on my voice.
我們會一起度過這個難關
We're going to get through this together.
我不會放棄你  琴
I'm not giving up on you, Jean.
家人之間就是這樣  彼此扶持
This is what family does. We take care of each other.
你是我的親人  琴
You're my family, Jean.
不管發生任何事
No matter what.
別再說了
Stop!
-瑞雯  -我喘不過氣
- Raven... - I can't catch my breath.
不
No.
我愛你
I love you.
什麼
What?
我
I...
瑞雯  別死
Raven, please.
瑞雯
Raven.
瑞雯  我愛你  瑞雯
Raven. I love you, Raven.
不
No.
人這一生  就是我與我周旋  都身處戰場
We are all at war, at war with ourselves,
而瑞雯這一生都在和自己對弈
and Raven had been waging that war for most of her life.
願她安息
I hope now she's found peace.
瑞雯到死都如此重情義
Raven died doing what she did best...
她死於幫助一個困境中的朋友
helping a friend, a friend in need.
她沒有離開
She is not gone.
她的精神永在  通過我
She lives on, through me,
我們
through us...
以及X戰警傳承下去
and through the spirit of the X-Men.
這是真的嗎
Is it true?
琴殺了她
Jean killed her?
她當時不是自己了
She didn't know what she was doing.
琴失控了
Jean lost control.
但她還是琴
But she-she's still Jean.
她還是我們的朋友
She's still our friend.
我們還是可以幫她  找到她
We can still help her. We can find her.
帶她回家
And bring her home.
我們一定要這麼做
That's... That's what we're gonna do, okay?
那不是意外  斯考特
It wasn't an accident, Scott.
她殺了瑞雯
She killed Raven.
即使你無法對自己  對孩子們承認這一點
Maybe you can't admit that to yourself or to them,
但事實就是如此
but it's the truth.
那不是琴  不是我認識的琴
That was not Jean, not the Jean I know.
有時  你想要相信別人不是那樣
Sometimes you want to believe people are something that they are not.
然而  等你覺悟時
And then, by the time you realize who they are...
一切都太遲了
it's too late.
我和瑞雯就是在這裡相識
Do you know, this is where I first met Raven.
她當時還是個孩子
She was just this little girl, and...
她偷闖進來  找東西吃
she'd broken in, looking for food.
我跟她說可以留下
I said she could stay,
這樣她就不用再挨餓了
and that she'd never have to go hungry again.
我還承諾讓她過上好日子
And then, I think I promised her a better life.
結果你把她害死了
And then you took it from her.
-你說什麼  -你聽到了
- I beg your pardon? - You heard me.
-漢克  -這都怪你  查爾斯
- Hank... - This is your fault, Charles.
她死了  都怪你
It's your fault she's dead.
你別不講理
Come on, that's not fair.
講理  別跟我來這一套
Fair? No, don't talk about fair.
你篡改了一個八歲小女孩的記憶
You messed with the mind of an eight-year-old girl.
你把所有痛苦與憤怒都埋藏起來
You pushed down all that pain and anger...
你覺得那些壓抑的情感會去哪兒
Where do you think it's gonna go?
我那樣是為了她好
I did that to help her.
-我做的一切都是為了孩子們  -行了  別狡辯了
- What I do, I do to help all of them. - Please, come on, please.
-你還是看不清自己的錯  -就是...
- You still can't see what you did wrong? - It's just...
你得面對現實  查爾斯  面對自己的錯
No, you need to face this, Charles! You need to face it.
你就承認吧  承認錯誤吧
Come on, admit it to me right now. Come on!
承認你錯了
Admit it!
查爾斯  求你就認錯吧
Charles, just admit you were wrong, please.
你還是無法認錯
You still can't.
希望這會讓你好過些  漢克
I really hope you feel better, Hank.
我剛安葬了自己的養妹
I hope that railing on me five minutes
你就朝我發洩  借此能讓你好過...
after I put my foster sister in the grave has made you feel...
我不是為了自己發洩
This isn't about me.
我肯認錯  查爾斯
You, know what? I know what I did wrong, okay, Charles?
她本打算離開
She was gonna leave.
瑞雯本來想離開  我說服她留下了
Raven was gonna leave, and I talked her out of it.
她看清了一件我們都沒看清的事
She saw what the rest of us didn't.
什麼事
And what was that?
我們一直以來都在保護孩子們不受外界傷害
This whole time, we've been trying to protect these kids from the world,
但其實  孩子們真正應該遠離的人是你
when really, we should've been protecting them from you.
我到底是怎麼了
I don't know what's happening to me.
為什麼
Why?
我為什麼會這麼做
Why did I do that?
-平民不許...  -聯調局
- No civilians past this... - FBI.
你們先出去
Give us the room.
你們是什麼人
And who are you supposed to be?
我們是來幫你的人  葛雷先生
We're the ones who are going to help you, Mr. Grey.
我不知道她會回來
I didn't know she was gonna come back.
我很抱歉搞成這樣
I'm sorry for all this.
沒事
It's okay.
我們就是想瞭解一下琴到底是個怎樣的人
We just wanna get an accurate picture of who Jean is.
說說看  你何時把她交給了變種人
Tell us about when you gave her to the mutant.
我還是
Maybe...
還是跟律師談一下吧
it might be better if I talk to a lawyer.
很抱歉  葛雷先生
I'm so sorry, Mr. Grey,
我要立刻瞭解她的一切
but I need to know everything about her now.
事情發展到這一步  實屬遺憾
This truly is an unfortunate development.
這話是什麼意思
Why-Why is that?
因為你不慘叫  我才能更好地理解你的話
Because it's so much easier to understand your language when you're not screaming.
來者何人
Who are you?
有何目的
What are you doing here?
回答我
Answer the question.
你退下
Leave her.
你怎麼來了
Why are you here?
你受傷了嗎
Are you hurt?
沒有
No.
你別見怪
You'll have to forgive them.
他們不太喜歡不速之客
They're not accustomed to uninvited guests.
請
Please.
從頭說起吧
Why don't you start at the beginning?
那是誰的血
Whose blood is that?
-什麼  -你襯衫上
- What? - On your shirt.
是誰的血
Whose blood is it?
我不是查爾斯
Look, I'm not Charles.
我不會讀心術
I can't read your mind.
你傷人無數
You hurt people.
-那都是以前的事了  -但你確實如此
- It's been a while. - But you did.
是  你為什麼來問我這件事
Yes. What did you come here to ask me?
你是怎麼停手了
How did you stop?
我這一生都活在仇恨之中
I've lived with vengeance my whole life.
我從小起
Ever since I was a child,
就慢慢失去了所有親人摯愛
I... lost everyone I ever loved, so...
我傷人
I hurt people.
殺人
Yes, killed people.
我以為殺死那些人  就能平復傷痛
Killed whatever I thought would make the pain go away.
但沒有
It didn't,
不管我送多少人去見閻王  都無法平復
no matter how many souls I sent under...
於是我收手了
so I stopped.
我不知道怎麼收手
I don't know how to stop.
我不知道自己到底怎麼了
I don't know what's happening to me.
我失控時
When I lose control...
就會出事  傷及他人
things happen, bad things...
傷害所愛之人
to people I love.
那是誰的血
Whose blood is that?
這不正是你此行目的嗎
Isn't that why you came here?
-你想讓我怎麼幫你  -我說不清
- What do you think I can do for you? - I don't know!
你可以  那是誰的血
Yes, you do. Whose blood is that?
-我不想說  -你傷人了嗎
- I don't wanna talk about it. - Did you hurt someone?
-拜託  我  -回我我  琴
- Please, I... - Answer the question, Jean.
-別追問了  埃裡克  你激怒我了  -很好
- Stop, Erik, you're making me angry. - Good!
我就是想激怒你
I want you to be angry.
-我要看看有什麼後果  琴  -我不想傷到你
- Show me what happens, Jean. - I don't wanna hurt you!
我要看看激怒你的後果是什麼
What happens when you're angry? Show me.
-讓我看看  -別說了
- Show me what... - Stop!
軍方來人了
We've got military.
就要降落了
Inbound.
待在這裡
Stay here.
兩架美軍直升機
Two birds. US.
讓大家冷靜  但做好防備
Tell everyone to stay calm, but ready.
好  別再靠近了
All right, that's far enough.
我們有權待在此地
We have a legal right to be here.
政府將這裡授權於我們
This land was given to us by the US government.
我們無意收回授權
We have no intention of taking it back.
我們不是來找你
We're not here for you.
我們來找一位X戰警  琴·葛雷
We're looking for one of the X-Men. Jean Grey.
我很久沒見過她了
I haven't seen her in a long time.
那你不介意我們四處看一下吧
Then you won't mind if we look around.
我沒有家了  都是拜你所措
I don't have a home. You made sure of that.
如果我不打招呼  就闖入你家
Would you mind if I came to your home...
家人之間就該這樣
This is what family does.
你介不介意呢
unannounced and uninvited?
你是我的親人  琴
You're my family, Jean.
是這樣
Look...
我知道你是誰
I know who you are.
-我不想挑事  -最好別挑事
- I don't wanna fight. - No, you don't.
那你就讓開
Then step aside.
我們和你  你家人  享有一樣的權利
We have the same rights as you and your family.
我說過了  我們不是來找你
And like I said, we're not here for you.
我們是來找那個放棄這些權利的女子
We're here for a girl who gave up those rights
她傷了一隊警員
when she attacked a squad of police officers.
那些警察也有家人
They have families, too.
看來你還不知情
Guess you didn't hear about that.
我們這裡看不到新聞  上尉
We don't get the news out here, Captain.
住手
Stop that.
我讓你住手
I said stop that right now!
-不是我  -是我
- It's not me. - It's me.
琴
Jean?
Jean!
趴下
Get down!
趕緊上直升機離開
Get in the chopper and go!
我撐不了多久
I can't hold it!
撤退  撤退
Fall back! Fall back!
快走  快撤退
Let's go, move, move!
快走  撤離  快離開
Let's go! Hook in! Move it! Come on!
-快走  快走  -走
- Let's go, let's go, let's go! - Come on!
把手給我  拉我一把
Give me your hand. Help me!
你走
Go!
-離開這裡  -我需要你的幫助
- Leave this place! - I need your help.
你不是保護這裡的變種人嗎
I thought you protected mutants here.
我確實保護他們  不受你的傷害
I am protecting them... from you.
你趕緊走
You need to leave.
走
Go!
今晚最新消息
Word coming late tonight that
國會正考慮設立變種人臨時拘留所
Congress is considering temporary mutant internment facilities
用來關押那些
for those whose powers have been deemed
其異能會傷害民眾的變種人
a clear and present danger to human citizens.
這是官方應對"琴·葛雷事件"之策
This coming on the heels of the Jean Grey incidents
她毀壞了兩處住宅區
which, after destroying two communities,
襲擊了警察與軍方人員
and attacking police and military personnel...
我是查爾斯·澤維爾
This is Charles Xavier.
我要和總統通話
I'd like to talk to the president.
澤維爾先生  本線路已作廢
Mr. Xavier, this phone will no longer be operational.
我得告訴他  別這麼做
I have to tell him not to do this.
沒必要將我們的成果都付之一炬
There's no need to throw away everything that we've accomplished.
要給我們機會...
You have to give us a chance and...
如果你破壞了任何東西
If you break something, anything,
我來修復
I can fix it.
不是一切都能修復
Not anything.
官方正在對葛雷進行國際搜捕
An international search is underway for Grey.
政府呼籲市民避免與其接觸
Authorities are urging citizens to keep their distance.
見到她的蹤跡  要立刻報警
Any sighting should be reported to the police immediately.
政府官員已經...
Government officials have...
這個人被電死了
This man was electrocuted...
你就這點本事嗎
Is that all you got?
再來一杯
Give me another.
你好  琴
Hello, Jean.
你沒法控制我的心智
You can't control my mind like theirs.
我跟他們不一樣
I'm not like them.
我也來一杯這個酒
Same, please.
你是怎麼找到我的
How did you find me?
我在政府裡有關係
Let's just say I have friends in high places.
你是誰
Who are you?
更應該問的是
The better question is...
你是誰
who are you?
你是那個對輪椅男言聽計從的驚慌小女孩
Are you a scared little girl who answers to a man in a chair...
還是這個星球上最強大的存在者
or are you the most powerful creature on the planet?
我不清楚自己是誰
I don't know who I am.
你清楚
Yes, you do.
你是個眾叛親離的女子
You're the girl who everyone abandons.
也許是我活該被離棄
Maybe they had good reason.
因為你體內的力量嗎
Because of what's inside you?
你畏懼是因為你覺得這種力量滋生邪惡
You're afraid of it because you think it makes you bad, evil,
你一直以來都被管束  做乖乖女
all the words you've been taught to keep you in line.
這些教導都是遠古時代  思維受限的男人們所創
Words created a very long time ago by men with very little minds.
他們無法理解你這種強大的存在
They can't begin to comprehend what you are.
你的X戰警隊友也無法理解
Even your X-Men.
你能理解嗎
And you can?
查爾斯
Charles?
查爾斯  查爾斯
Charles? Charles!
-漢克不在班上  -什麼
- Hey, Hank's not in class. - What?
漢克沒去教課
Hank's not in class.
你去他宿舍看過了嗎
Did you check his quarters?
看過了  也沒人
Yeah, he's not there either.
其他人呢
Where are the rest of them?
我一人前來
No, I'm alone.
查爾斯沒跟來嗎
What, no Charles?
如果你來找琴
If you're looking for Jean...
她走了
she's gone.
我知道
No, I know that.
那你為何事而來  漢克
Then why are you here, Hank?
你耳目遍及天下
You have eyes and ears around the world
能幫你找到變種人
to help you find mutants for this place.
我想讓你幫我找到琴
I want you to help me find Jean.
我何必找她
I've no reason to find her.
不是為了我
Not for me.
為了瑞雯
Do it for Raven.
她派你過來的嗎
Did she send you?
你還不知情
You don't know?
知道什麼  漢克
Know what, Hank?
瑞雯死了
Raven's dead.
琴殺了她
Jean killed her.
你得幫我找到琴
I need you to help me find Jean.
我找到她  我會殺了她
If I find her, I'll kill her.
我知道
I know.
他們知道我是誰
They know who I am?
對
Yes.
他們不怕我
And they're not afraid of me?
這裡只有你才懼怕自己的異能
The only person here afraid of your power... is you.
召集其他人
Go, gather the others.
如果她控制不了  就將其毀掉
If she can't control it, then we will destroy it.
這就是你要給我看的嗎
This is what you wanted to show me?
不是
No.
這才是我要給你看的景象
This is what I want to show you.
太空中進入你體內的不是太陽耀斑
What entered you in space was not a solar flare.
而這也不是一場意外
And it was not an accident.
這種力量被你吸引
It was drawn to you.
是什麼東西
What-What was it?
一種威力無比純粹的宇宙能量
A pure and unimaginably powerful cosmic force.
我們看到這種力量進入你的體內
We saw it enter you in space.
我們當時追隨這種力量  親眼所見  琴
We were there, Jean, following that force.
為什麼
Why?
因為這是激活宇宙萬物的生命火花
Because it's the spark that gave life to the universe...
那股烈焰摧毀了我的星球
and the flame that consumed my world.
族人中的倖存者一直追尋這種力量
What remains of my people searched the stars for that power,
想要控制這種力量
to control it,
但這種力量所到之處  儘是毀滅
but it destroyed everything it ever came into contact with.
直到遇見你
Until you.
為什麼是我
Why me?
因為你不知道自己多麼強大
Because you're stronger than you know.
因為你天賦異稟  琴
Because you're special, Jean.
有我幫忙  你可以控制體內的這種力量
With my help, you could control what's inside you.
駕馭這種力量  創造全新的世界
Harness that power to create whole new worlds...
化塵為水
turn dust into water...
化水為生命
water into life.
你宿命如此  注定成就不凡  琴
It's your destiny, Jean, to become something greater...
演化成銀河系中最強大的能力者
to evolve into the greatest force in the galaxy.
我說過  他們永遠無法企及你
I told you they could never understand you.
而面對無法掌握的未知  他們懼怕
And what they don't understand, they fear.
但凡他們懼怕
And what they fear...
就會想辦法摧毀
They seek to destroy.
瑞雯死得痛苦嗎
Did Raven suffer?
還算痛快
Not for long.
我們以前關係不合  但是
I know we've had our differences in the past, but...
我們都愛瑞雯
We both love Raven.
對
Yes.
她生前  我們都很愛她
Yes, we did.
發現那個女人的蹤跡了
There's been a sighting of the girl.
哪裡
Where?
紐約
New York.
到了之後  自會有人幫我們找到她
We'll have eyes on the ground when we get there.
該動身了
It's time.
我們知道琴的位置了
We know where Jean is.
你不是說無法追蹤她嗎
I thought you said you couldn't track her.
不是我找到她的
It wasn't me who found her.
而是埃裡克
It was Erik.
漢克跟他在一起
Hank's with him.
他們去找她了  打算殺了她
They're on their way to her, and they're gonna kill her.
還會殺掉阻擋他們的人
And anyone who stands in their way.
科特  就只帶我和斯考特過去
Kurt, I'd like you to take Scott and I there, but that's all.
把我們帶過去之後  你就走
I want you to leave us there and then come home.
我呢
And me?
我不是以X戰警的身份跟你說話
I'm not talking to you now as X-Men.
我和斯考特會為琴而戰  你不用去
Scott and I will go and fight for Jean without you.
我心意已決
End of discussion.
暴風女  我失去太多所愛之人
Storm, I have lost so many of the people I love.
我不會讓你涉險
I'm not going to ask you to go.
我要去
I am.
我們需要你
We need you.
我需要你
I need you.
-我定當鼎力相助  -聽著
- I've got your back. - Look...
我心意已決
End of discussion.
科特  閉上眼
Kurt, close your eyes.
我給你看目的地
I'll show you our destination.
他們在哪兒
Where are they?
她在裡面
She's in there.
你好啊  老朋友
Hello, old friend.
別套近乎了  查爾斯
Save the "Old friend" shit, Charles.
別擋路
And stay out of my way.
她的所為  我很抱歉
I'm sorry for what she did.
但我不能讓你進去
But I can't let you go in there.
你總是不停道歉  查爾斯
You're always sorry, Charles.
還每次都來說教那一套
And there's always a speech.
但沒人在乎了
But nobody cares anymore.
如果在這裡開戰  人們會把我們當成大魔頭
We do this here, now, they'll see us as monsters.
紐約街頭上鬥毆的殘暴怪物
Violent freaks, fighting on the streets of New York.
我說什麼來著
What did I tell you?
該死  你的家園將不復存在
Damn it, man, your homeland will be gone.
你努力的一切都將付諸東流
Everything you care about.
省省吧
Save it.
你敢動她  我就殺了你
If you touch her, I will fucking kill you.
別這麼做  埃裡克
Don't do this, Erik.
人死不能復生  殺了琴也無濟於事
Killing Jean will not bring Raven back.
這個女人必須死
The girl dies.
科特  來幫我
Kurt, I need you!
科特  把我帶進去
Kurt, get me inside.
不是只有你會控心術
You're not the only one who can control minds.
科特
Kurt!
他們來殺你了  別讓他們得逞
They're coming to kill you. You're not gonna let them.
你要反擊
You're gonna fight back.
連通你體內的那股力量
Feel the power inside you.
那股力量就是你的化身
The power is you.
拖住他們
Hold them!
我知道那是誰的血了
I know whose blood that was.
你對我下了逐客令
You cast me out.
現在又來取我性命
Now you come here to kill me?
沒錯
That's right.
你連殺我都做不到
And you couldn't even do that.
我來教教你吧
Let me show you how.
斯考特  幫個忙
Scott, a little help?
科特
Kurt!
科特  科特
Kurt! Kurt?
-你還好吧  -不好
- You all right? - No!
過來  趕緊把我帶進去
Come here! Get me in that house now!
你也是來殺我的嗎
Have you come to kill me, too?
絕不是
Never.
琴  我永遠不會那麼做
Jean, never!
我辜負了你  我知道
I failed you. I know that, but...
但這不是你
this isn't you.
科特
Kurt!
-琴  拜託  -你根本不瞭解我
- Jean, please! - You have no idea who I am.
我一手把你養大
I've raised you since you were a little girl.
我瞭解
I think I do.
她不再是小孩子了
She's not your little girl anymore.
你...
Who...
你是誰
What are you?
琴  回想一下我對你的教導
Jean, please try and remember what I taught you.
你能夠控制
You can control it.
只要專注  你就無所不能
You can do anything you set your mind to.
那你就證明給我看
So show me.
走過來
Walk to me.
我是個瘸子
You know I can't.
不
No!
別這樣  琴
Please, Jean.
求你了
Please.
我沒法對你使用讀心術了
I can't see in your mind anymore...
但你可以讀我的心
but you can see in mine.
看一下吧
So look.
琴  看看吧
Jean, look.
如何使用上天賜予你的禮物[天賦]And what you choose to do with your gift,
完全取決於你
well, that's entirely up to you.
這裡可以是你的新家
This could be your new home.
我們可以成為你新的家人
We could be your new family.
不
No!
因為你沒有毛病
Because you are not broken.
你會帶走她
Then you'll take her?
對
Yes.
不
No!
我可以更好地幫她
I can help her in ways that you can't.
誰都幫不了她
She can't be helped.
她無藥可救了
She's a lost cause.
不  她不是
No, she's not.
只要有人關愛她  相信她
As long as there's someone to care for her, who believes,
她就還有希望
then there's still hope.
還有希望
Then there... There's still hope.
我就知道  我就知道你本性未泯
I knew. I knew you were still in there.
他只是給你看了你的過去
He just showed you your past.
跟隨我  一起邁入你的未來
Follow me... into your future.
不
No.
武器使用麻醉劑
Set weapons to neutralize.
我沒想獲得這種異能
I never asked for this.
這一切都非我所願
Any of it.
我跨越星系追尋這種力量  你卻想棄之如敝屣
I traveled to the stars for a gift that you don't want.
那你就拿走吧
Then take it.
求你
Please.
放我自由
Free me.
我試試看
I'll try.
住手  你會殺了她
Stop it. You're going to kill her.
你們的生命如同草芥
Your lives mean nothing.
你們的世界將屬於我們
Your world will be ours.
你要殺光所有人
You'd kill us all.
對
Yes.
琴  你得放手
Jean, you have to let go.
琴  放開
Jean, let go!
快放開  琴  放開
Let go, Jean. Let go!
放開
Let go!
那邊有一個  放倒他
There's one! Get him!
琴
Jean!
Jean.
琴
Jean?
琴  琴
Jean, Jean.
-查爾斯  怎麼了  -不知道  我沒法進入她的大腦
- Charles, what's wrong? - I don't know. I can't read her mind.
快  出去  把他帶出去
Come on, out! Take him out!
快出去  快  各位  快走
Come on, out, out! You guys, come on. Train.
你們四個跟我走
You four with me, let's go!
-我們走  -行動
- Let's go! - Come on, move!
行動  快  快
Come on. Move, move, move!
-她還活著  -斯考特  你得把她帶出去
- She's alive. - Scott, you have to get her out.
你得...  不
You have to... No!
目標已全部搞定
We're clear!
最後一個
Last one.
搜索最後三處街區  我們走
We need a clean sweep on the last three blocks. Let's go!
我家孩子以前很崇拜你們
My kid used to be a fan.
瑞雯說得對
Raven had the right of it.
大惡人不是琴
Jean was never the villain.
而是我
I was.
我當初就不該騙她
I should never have lied to her.
我錯了
I was wrong.
但她體內的這股力量
But this power inside of her,
非我安排
I never put that there.
我絕不會有意傷害她
I would never do anything intentionally to hurt her.
我的初衷並非惡意  琴也如此
That isn't me and this is not Jean.
我們還是能把她救回來
We can still save her.
她還留存著本性
She's still Jean inside.
離變種管制中心還有十英里
We're 10 miles out from Mutant Containment Center.
準備好轉移囚犯
Prepare for prisoner transfer.
她被什麼控制
What exactly is controlling her?
不清楚
I don't know.
但那個女人  那個生物體
But this woman, this... thing...
嘗到了這種力量的甜頭
has had a taste of that power,
她還會再回來吸取這種力量
and she'll be coming back for more.
她會再回來找琴
She'll be coming back for Jean.
很好  讓她來
Good. Let her.
她會為了吸取力量而殺死她
She'll kill her to get it.
但我保證  殺戮不會到此為止
But I promise you, the killing will not end there.
瑞雯還活著  不會希望發生這種事
That's not what Raven would have wanted.
你心知這點
You know that.
你們倆都清楚
You both do.
隊長  你看到了嗎
Skipper, are you seeing this?
A1小隊  多名敵人來襲
Alpha One, you have multiple hostiles onboard.
他們正向車尾移動
They're heading towards the back.
-打開四號門  五號門  -收到
- Open four to five. - Copy that.
你們倆  跟我來
All right, you two, come with me.
其餘人留守  看住犯人
The rest of you, stay here, guard the prisoners!
別犯傻  你們需要我們
Don't be fools! You need our help!
快  鎖門
Lock it down! Now!
可惡的變種來救你們了
Goddamn muties come to spring you.
他們不是變種人
They're not mutants.
放了我們  你們會需要我們
Free us, you're going to need our help.
只有我們出手  你們才能活命
We're the only chance you have.
閉嘴吧
Keep your mouth shut.
求救  求救
Mayday! Mayday!
匯報一下變種人敵情
What's the status on those mutants?
我們正在撤退  他們不是...
We're falling back now! They're not...
什麼
What?
他們不是什麼
They're not what?
-他們不是變種人  -他們來找琴了
- They're not mutants! - They're here for Jean.
準備開火
Get ready to open fire!
你家孩子沒看錯我們
Your kid was right about us.
我們能救你們
We could help you!
放開我們
Please!
開火
Fire!
後面還有敵人
There's more!
我們的目標只是那個女人  讓開
We only want the girl. Step aside.
不要
No!
你幹什麼
What are you doing?
瑞雯還活著  就一定會這麼做
What Raven would have.
斯考特  把我帶到琴那裡
Scott, get me to Jean!
塞琳
Selene!
漢克
Hank!
幫一下暴風女
Help Storm!
不不  別死啊
No, no, no, no, no, please.
別死啊  別啊
Don't die. No.
到了  到了
That's it, that's it, that's it.
斯考特  守住入口
Scott, guard the entrance.
琴  醒醒
Jean, wake up.
琴  醒醒  你得趕緊醒過來
Jean, wake up. You have to wake up now.
漢克
Hank!
我不想跟你打
I have no desire to fight you.
這話我常聽
I get that a lot.
你之前想讓她死
You wanted her dead.
我改變心意了
I had a change of heart.
我當時是想保護你
I was trying to protect you.
我不想讓你經歷那些痛苦  但是
I was trying to keep the pain away, but...
你只是將其埋藏起來了
You just buried it.
琴
Jean.
這是哪兒
Where...?
這是在我的大腦裡嗎
Are we inside my mind?
這裡比我的大腦要平靜
It's more peaceful than mine.
我當年那麼對你  我很抱歉
I'm so sorry for what I did to you.
我知道
I know.
我當時只是一心想保護你
All I ever wanted was to protect you
讓你過上常人的生活
and give you what you deserved.
擁有一個美好的童年
What every child deserves.
一個美好的家
A family.
對
Yeah.
我知道你是出於愛才這樣做
I know you did what you did out of love.
我原諒你了
I forgive you.
我知道我現在要做什麼了
I know what I need to do now.
做什麼
And what is that?
保護我的家人
Protect my family.
琴  琴
Jean. Jean.
你想要這股力量嗎
You want this power?
那就給你
You're gonna get it.
琴
Jean!
你無法控制
You can't control it.
如果你殺了我  也會殺死大家
If you kill me, you'll kill them all.
情義使你不堪一擊
Your emotions make you weak.
琴
Jean.
夠了
Enough.
琴
Jean!
你錯了
You're wrong.
情義使我無所不能
My emotions make me strong.
她消失了
She's gone.
她
She...
她自由了
She's free.
琴·葛雷天賦青少年學校
我清楚自己是誰了
I know who I am now.
我不是別人眼中期待的模樣
I am not simply what others want me to be.
我不是無法逃脫宿命的人
I am not destined to a fate I can't control.
我進化超越了
I evolved beyond this world.
這不是我的終結
This is not the end of me...
也不是X戰警的終結
or the X-Men.
這是一個嶄新的開始
It's a new beginning.
別跑  安全第一
Hey, slow down. Safety first.
退休生活如何
How's retirement treating you?
你怎麼來了  埃裡克
What are you doing here, Erik?
我來見見老朋友
I came to see an old friend.
來一局如何
Fancy a game?
今天不來了  謝了
No, not today. Thank you.
很久之前  你救了我一命
A long time ago, you saved my life.
然後給了我一個家
Then you offered me a home.
我如今也想這麼做
I'd like to do the same for you.
就來一局
Just one game.
畢竟故交一場
For old times' sake.
我會手下留情
I'll go easy on you.
你可不會
No, you won't.
原創翻譯  雙語字幕
最新連載海外影視劇下載
請登陸 www.YYeTs.com
僅供交流學習  禁止商用盈利
翻譯    Ievo    Margaery   余歡  77 imyours
翻譯   兔牙Bobby貓☆ 開學歡樂多！！
校對    兔牙Bobby貓★ Forever21
時間軸   兔牙Bobby貓☆ DNA重編輯
後期     8T
總監    兔牙Bobby貓 ? 基因新變異